CIA director's notetaker in the final
principles committee meeting the night
before we attacked Iraq. So it's chaired
by the vice president. We've got
secretary of state Colin Powell,
National Security Adviser uh Cona Rice,
Secretary of Defense Don Rumsfeld, the
chairman and vice chairman of the joint
chiefs, a whole bunch of big mucky
mucks. And uh General Tommy Franks gave
the order of battle briefing. That's how
he started off the the meeting. I'm
sitting directly behind George Tennant,
the CIA director. And General Franks
finishes his briefing by saying his
exact words, "If all goes as planned, we
can be in Tehran by August." And George
turns off his microphone and he leans
back and he says to me, "Did he say
Thran or did he say Baghdad?" And I
said, "He said Thran."
>> Yeah. At the end of it, as we were
getting up to leave the meeting, one of
the guys from the one of the senior
senior directors at the National
Security Council says,
"As soon as we cross that border
tomorrow, they're going to throw flowers
at us." And I went back to the I was
working for the deputy director at the
time and he said, "How was the principal
committee meeting?" And I said, "Did you
know we were going to invade Iran?" And
he said, "Are they still talking about
that? We're not going to invade Iran."
And I said, "Do these people know
nothing about history?" And he said, 'N
no, they know nothing about history.
Here we are now 23 years later and the
president of the United States was
convinced easily by all reports that as
soon as the first missile were to fly,
the Iranian government would collapse
like a house of cards. And anybody with
any brains at all knew that was
ridiculous. And that was a Netanyahu
talking point going back to the 1990s.
So now here we are almost out of
missiles, unable to protect two aircraft
carrier strike forces and no end in
sight to this conflict.
>> But hey, week one, we won already.
>> Yeah, we won. We won like four times
already.
>> Don't forget we already won.
>> Somebody asked me the other day, "How do
you think this ends?" I said, "It ends
when we wake up one morning and we look
at Truth Social and the president said
in the middle of the night, it's all
over. We won. I'm bringing everybody
home. We win. big parade on Constitution
Avenue and sure enough the next day
that's what he said for like the fourth
time.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, we won. It's over.
>> Doesn't say that at the gas pump, you
know.
>> No, it [clears throat] does not.
>> And um yeah, the straits still closed. I
you know, I just don't know how long
people can be lied to before they open
their eyes. I mean, they're going to
feel it. They are feeling it, you know,
and uh it's pretty obvious. And we, you
know, I think he got dog walked into
that war. I don't think that he wanted
to go to war.
>> I don't think he did. I don't think he
had a choice which is the scary part.
Like I don't think we have full
sovereignty. And so that to me is the
part that I think we really need to look
into. It's like why are we actually in
this war? Because they even said so the
only reason we attacked is because
Israel is going to attack so we had to
like what is that? That is not a
relationship of a country that we are
providing a ton of aid to. Like we
should have a say in what they do.
>> And it seems like it's the other way
around. I'm just looking at this like a
completely one-sided relationship. I
feel like
>> we're like a battered wife. It's like
what are we doing? You know, like they
keep they keep screwing us over. They
sell our secrets. They steal our
uranium. Like, how many times can this
country screw us over? And you were in
the CIA. Like, I mean, what was your
experience with the I mean, because I
know it wasn't good. I've seen a little
bit, but you know, I want to hear it
from the horse's mouth here.
>> Yeah. It was not good at all. Not only
do we did we not like working with the
Israel Mossad. Uh we we didn't permit
them in the building.
>> Yeah.
>> It was the like literally the very first
thing that I learned when I got to the
agency. We do not brief Mossad in the
building. They're not welcome here
because
>> stealing bugging, right?
>> They would always come with gifts,
right? They come with a big seal of the
CIA. First of all, they're everywhere.
We don't need any more seals of the CIA,
at least of one, at least of all one
coming from the Israeli embassy. And it
weighs three times what it should weigh
cuz it's packed with batteries and
listening devices. And we're like,
"Guys, you you you got to stop doing
this." And then they laugh. Oh, all in
good fun. No, it's not. You're trying to
bug the conference room again. So we
have to you know rent office space and
um and we just meet with him in the
office. I I tell this story too. The
first liaison briefing I ever gave I was
only six weeks on the job was to Mossad
and Shinbet and so because I was the
youngest newest analyst. I went last. So
the chief analyst starts first. Then the
political guy, the military guy, the oil
guy, this guy, that guy comes to me. And
because I was overt at the time, I was
not undercover. I used my true name. I
said, "I'm John Kuryako. I'm here to
brief you on, you know, X, Y, and Z."
And the guy, the Mossad guy, has his
glasses like this. And he he says,
"Spell your name." So I spell my name
and he goes, [clears throat]
"You are Jewish." [laughter] And I said,
"I am not recruitable. Don't even think
about it. I am not recruitable." I go
back to the office. My boss said, "How
was it?" I said, "Man, I am so mad right
now. This guy practically cold pitched
me right there in the office in front of
everybody." and he laughs and he says,
"They've done that to every one of us.
Every one of us in our first briefings
with them. It's like they can't help
themselves." And I've told the story
many, many times that I had a colleague
who went to Israel and and was an overt
employee. So he the the chief took him
to Mossad and said, "This is my guy.
He's a CIA officer. His wife is going to
work with you guys. He's going to go to
the university and learn how to speak
Arabic." Okay? So no problems, no
threats, no nothing.
The first time they went to dinner at
the ambassador's house, they came back
after the dinner and all their living
room furniture had been rearranged just
as a just as a message that we can do
anything we want and there's nothing you
can do about it. So months later, they
go to another uh dinner at the
ambassador's residence. They come back
to the house and people had
it's a family show. People had defecated
in all of the toilets in their house and
just left it unflushed.
>> Wow. And then another year passes.
They're getting ready to leave to come
back to the States and the ambassador
has a going away party for them. They
get back to the house. Someone had gone
in the house, cut the dog's tail off,
and then wrapped it in medical gauze and
tape and the dog is whimpering under the
dining room table. And these are our
best friends in the world, right?
>> That's crazy.
>> This is how they treat us.
>> And every time it happens, we have to go
to the Mossad and say, "Stop harassing
our people." And then they say, "Okay,
okay." And they back off for a year,
maybe two, and then the whole thing
starts again.
>> Yeah, that's insane. I mean, how were
you treated with other foreign
countries? Like even ones that we
weren't allies with? I feel like it
would be better than
>> completely professionally. No problems
at all. I literally never did I have a
problem with the foreign intelligence
service ever, except the Israelis just
cold pitching me right there in front of
all my colleagues.
>> Yeah. I think that level of arrogance
should tell you a lot.
>> Mhm.
>> You know,
>> and they know they know that there's no
downside to it. They're not going to be
punished in any way.
>> Yeah.
>> Not in any way. Nobody liked working
with them. You just couldn't trust them.
>> What do people say when you tell that
story? Because that's that's pretty
compelling.
>> Well, it's funny. The people I know are
interested and they say, "Oh my god,
that's terrible. It's a shame. It's good
that you're telling the story." People I
don't know call me an anti-semite,
threaten me with death, call me a Jew
hater. I got day before yesterday. I'm a
Jew hater apparently.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, that's actually so on TMZ
>> he was gonna switch over to Jew hater
because I had issue with the term
anti-semite because I'm like, well, you
know,
>> well, the Arabs are semi.
>> That's what [laughter] I'm saying. Yeah,
exactly. So, like Israel and you know,
and the Jews over, they're actually the
most anti-semitic people, you know, on
the planet because they're killing all
the semmites, right? So, I had issue
with the term and I think the term has
been weaponized. So, 100%
>> I didn't want to be called that. And so,
the other uh host was like, "Okay, we'll
just say Jew hater." and the main host
who was Jewish like no no no no no we're
not we're not losing this term and it
was like this you you saw this like
battle in real time and it's weird
because you know the word anti-semite is
kind of been hijacked to mean Jew hater
so really like that's to me when I think
of anti-semite I think of Jew hater
because that's what they've turned the
word into
>> and the fact that he wouldn't accept
that which would be a more descriptive
thing I mean that's you know basically
what he wanted to call me which isn't
accurate because I you know I I don't
hate all Jews I don't think that every
Jew is responsible for all this And in
fact, I'm, you know, I have Jews that
are friends. And so, you know, it's like
I mean, Bobby Fischer, he was like 100%
Jewish and he said the Jews are like
trying to ruin the world, you know, and
you got guys like Max Blumenth all that
are calling this out. So, it's like, you
know, it's not a complete monolith. Um,
I acknowledge that, but they it's weird
because they want to act like it's a
monolith. Yeah. You know, they want to
treat it like, you know, every Jew is a
part of the tribe and is protected and
if you say one thing about this Jew,
you're saying about all Jews and if you
say something about Israel, you're
saying it about all Jews. So they're
actually the ones that are pushing this
narrative of a monolith. It's not us.
It's like it's them because you know the
fact that they would coin that you know
any criticism of Israel as anti-semitic
literally says that they are saying that
if you criticize this country you're
criticizing all Jews. So it's weird.
It's once again this hypocrisy of like
they can say these things but if you say
it you're an anti-semite.
>> I went on the Pierce Morgan show the
other day. I I've been something of a
regular on that show and I I appeared
with General Danny Ayalon uh the former
head of the MSAD and uh Alan Dersuit who
hates me and gem
>> and Scott Horton who's one of the great
thinkers of our time I believe a great
libertarian thinker and um
>> it's just part of my personality that I
I don't interrupt people. I was always
taught that that was just a rude thing
to do. I I generally don't interrupt and
that show is all about interrupting. So,
I just kind of sit there and let the
rest of them go at it. And finally,
Pierce says to me, "Well, let me ask
John a couple of questions. John, do you
think that Hamas is a terrorist group?"
And I said, "Well, I think that it it is
essentially a a freedom fighting group,
but as it pertains to attacking
civilians on October 7th, yes, if the
point was to attack civilians, that's an
act of terrorism. That's the definition
of terrorism." Um, and he says, "Do you
believe that u that it was a terrorist
attack?" attack. I said, "In part, it
was a terrorist attack because it
specifically targeted a music festival
with a purpose of of killing or injuring
civilians for a political purpose." So,
yeah, that's the definition of of a
terrorist attack. He said, "Then what's
your problem with Israel?" And I said,
"Pice, you cannot have as a policy to
just kill everybody. That's not a
policy. That's called genocide. There's
a word for that. You cannot kill
everybody."
>> Yeah. Well, especially when they allowed
that to happen and they funded Hamas and
you know we can go into all that
>> and there were indic they funded Hamas
number one and that's a proven fact that
was a policy decision taken by Benjamin
Netanyahu but number two there were the
there were weeks full of intelligence
indicating that an attack was coming
>> and Idomar Bengavir who's supposed to be
the big mastermind of you know security
in Israel and who's really just a war
criminal um said no
>> the worst by the way the worst He's
worse than Netanyahu.
>> He's worse. But he insisted that the
attack was coming in the West Bank. And
I believe that the man is not that
stupid. He knew it was coming in Gaza.
And they were looking for something that
would allow them to just kill everybody
>> 100%. And you know, it's shown in their
response time, six hours to respond to
that. And then when they do respond,
they kill their own citizens, you know,
pump up the numbers. So, I'm I'm glad
that you didn't cave to that because I
think that what they try and do is
establish a framework of like, okay,
Hamas are terrorists, that makes them
the bad guys, so then Israel's the good
guys, right? And they want to just make
this very black and white. I'm glad that
you didn't fall into that trap because
it's an easy one to fall into is just
saying, oh yes, I I accept that Hamas is
really bad. And it's like, uh, look,
maybe they did some bad things. I'm sure
they did. I I you know I saw some things
that they did which were were bad, but
like if you really kind of look at it
objectively, I think it was over 400
Palestinian civilians were killed in
Gaza earlier that year, right? And then
if you look at the actual numbers of how
many civilians were killed during
October 7th, it's like under 400 because
you can't count people that are in the
IDF or reserve IDF people. No.
>> Um and then you also obviously can't
count the people that Israel killed with
their hellfire missiles, shelling
kabotas with the tanks. So when you
really dig into it, it's like, was it
actually that bad? Was it a response to
what had already happened? Because if
they killed less civilians than had been
killed on their side, then is it a
response? Is it a terrorist attack? I
mean, obviously it's bad to kill
civilians. No two ways about that. But
that didn't stop Israel from killing,
you know, how many civilians, right?
Like we don't even have a count. Some
some counts are up to 400,000. Like I
mean, the whole place is rubble. They
bombed every single working hospital.
They've bombed 90% of the schools. They
bombed all the churches. It's like, you
know, Hamas was there. Hamas was there.
I was like, "How many times you got to
hear that?" And I don't even care if a
moss is there. That doesn't give you the
right to, you know, blow up all the
children's schools. It doesn't give you
the right to blow up every single
working hospital in the area. It's like,
you know, the example I would give is
like, okay, you know, if if your
daughter, your son, they were in school
and there's a school shooter, you know,
unequivocally, hey, he's a bad guy. So,
what if they just blow up the whole
[__] school? You know, they got the
they got the shooter. Like, is that an
acceptable, you know, answer for you?
Your daughter's dead. You know, what
like what are we talking about here? So,
um I just don't their whole narrative is
just all nonsense when you actually dig
into it, right? Because there's no
beheaded babies. There's no babies. It's
just all nonsense. And so, yeah, they
try and frame it like that. That's what
I see is like a a a kind of like a
strangle hold on history. Um and what
they do is they try and create this
narrative that justifies their actions.
>> Um by accusing other people of things
that they are either doing or have done
after the fact. Dan, um, one of the
things that I think most observers of
foreign policy recognize, have
recognized over the years is that Israel
thrives on regional chaos, right? Israel
is safer when Iraq is in chaos. Israel
is safer when Syria's in chaos or
Libya's in chaos or now Iran is in
chaos. What's the endgame there? You
can't have chaos all the time in
perpetuity.
Well, I mean, if you accept their
Greater Israel project and that's what
they want to do, it's hard to steal land
without distractions. Um, it allows
justifications. Um, also turmoil in the
region distracts from what they're doing
to the Palestinians. Um, so, you know,
and also they don't want peace. This
idea that like, oh, you know, just let
us let the Jews have this piece of land
and, you know, everybody's attacking.
It's just nonsense. Like, they're
constantly the aggressors. And so I look
at this and I'm just like I don't know
of any other country other than us that
has bombed seven different countries in
a year, you know, other than Israel. So
it's like
>> I don't know. I I just I don't think
that they've ever wanted peace. Um
they're a terrorist nation and they you
know said this numerous times founded by
terrorists. Um and so yeah, I just I
think that as long as we are supporting
them and um allowing them to commit all
these terrorist acts, I mean they're
going to continue to be arrogant
[__] they're going to be, you know,
everybody acts like, oh, well, it's the
only democracy in the region region. And
I'm like, they are the only terrorists
in the region. They're causing all these
problems. And Americans just aren't
they're just not familiar with it. And
so, it's been framed to them that, you
know, uh, Muslims are bad. You know,
Israel's good.
>> You know, that's another thing I don't
understand, too. You're right about
that. Americans are led to believe that
just as a blanket statement, Muslims are
bad. I spent much of my adult life in
the Middle East and um you know our
relations our foreign relations with
almost all of the Middle Eastern
countries are very very tight very close
and good. You know we have a so-called
special relationship with the Saudis.
Whether that's true or not that's what
it's called. Our relations with Kuwait
are very strong. Bahrain is the
headquarters of the fifth fleet. Gutter
hosts the largest air force American air
force base in the world. The UAE, I
would argue that our relationship with
the UAE is closer than with than it is
with any of those other countries. The
Omanis, we've turned to the Omanis for
decades to be to be the middleman in our
relations with, you know, the Iranians
and with others. Um, we're we're joined
at the hip with the Egyptians, uh, with
the Moroccans, with the Tunisians. We
have great relations. So, how is it that
somehow the Muslims always seem to be
the bad guys, especially in American
foreign policy? I just
>> You want the honest answer? I mean, it's
Jewish propaganda that [laughter] is. I
mean, it comes from Hollywood. It's
because every time, you know, growing
up, you see uh terrorists, they're
always Muslim. They always have, you
know, a KFA or, you know, whatever. And
it's programming, man. Like, I was in
the military. I did, you know, three
months of boot camp. And in that three
months, I changed dramatically. So, what
does 30 years of programming do to you?
Um, I always thought Muslims were a
problem. I really did. Like growing up I
was like, you know, especially when I
was in the military, I'm like, "Oh,
these Hajis, you know, blah blah blah."
They have all these names for them.
Yeah.
>> Some of which I can't say on air, you
know, but they're bad and it dehumanizes
them, right? And so when you when guys
come back from war, you know, guys that
I went through, you know, training with,
whatever, come back and, you know, talk
brag about, you know, these Muslims they
killed. It's kind of like a badge of
honor and it's a way to justify the
things that they did. I really believe
that a lot of the PTSD comes from coming
back and realizing like
>> maybe these weren't the bad guys, you
know, and and and Rob O'Neal talked
about that actually. I heard him on one
podcast where he kicked in the door some
guy's house, bedroom, whatever, and guy
went for a gun and he shot him and he
was thinking about that. He's like,
"Hey, what if, you know, what if that
had been me? You know, what would I have
done? I would have grabbed my gun and,
you know, he would have shot me. And
what if I had something in common with
that guy? And what if we would have, you
know, had a laugh over coffee and
whatever?" And it's like, would he have
grabbed that gun if I didn't kick the
door into his bedroom? And why did I
kick the door in his, you know what I
mean? Like, you start asking yourself
these questions. I mean, Muslims have
always treated me with respect. And I'm
sure there's bad ones, you know, and
everybody wants to look at like, oh, but
the Muslim rape gangs in the UK and
Europe and everything else. And that's
once again, it's kind of pushing this
narrative. And it's like, yes, Muslims
are for sure causing problems over
there, but no different than the
Mexicans coming across the border and
they're mostly Christian, you know, and
the uh and the Ethiopians coming from
Ethiopia, you know, they're mostly I
mean, Africa is mostly Christian, right?
And it's not because they believe in
Jesus or they're, you know, came over
with their Bible, they're causing
problems. No, it's because they're poor
and they're coming from a country that,
you know, doesn't have strong culture.
They have no affinity to the new, you
know, um, country or state or wherever
they're going into. Um, and so that to
me is the source of the problem. It's
not because they read the Quran. You
know, I I've read parts of the Quran and
I mean, I've talked to a lot of Muslims
and rape is against, you know, their
religion in any way, shape, or form. So,
u, the only religion I've actually seen
where rape is excused is in Judaism in
the Talmud. Thank you for watching. This
is the deep state and remember to always
always ask the questions that the
government wants you to forget. This
conversation was a perfect example of
that. I'm John Kuryaku. We'll see you
next time.